Guide to the Korean War Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Korean War collection
1951-1953
MS 742
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
An artificial collection of leaflets, radio scripts, newspapers, and posters produced by American, Chinese, and Korean governments for use during the Korean War as propaganda devices.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Henry Millholland, 1974; and others.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of propaganda leaflets, newspapers, and posters distributed to Chinese and North Korean military forces[by the U.S. Army. Far East Command. Psychological Warfare Division. First Radio Broadcasting and Leaflet Group?]during the Korean War. English translations are attached to each item. Also included are mimeographed copies of radio propaganda broadcasts made during June-August, 1952. There are also a few propaganda leaflets distributed to American and South Korean military forces by the North Korean government.
Armed Forces; Korean War, 1950-1953; Leaflets dropped from aircraft; Propaganda, American; Propaganda, Chinese; Propaganda -- Korea; Asia; Millholland, Henry
- Inventory
  - Korean leaflets [only partial holdings in each number series]
    - Nos. 1-999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Nos. 1000-1099 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Nos. 1100-1149 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Nos. 1150-1199 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Nos. 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Nos. 1300-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Nos. 2000-2699 (excluding newspapers) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Nos. 2700-2999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nos. 3000-4999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Nos. 5000-5999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Nos. 6000-6999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nos. 7000-7999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Nos. 8000-8299 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Nos. 8300-8399 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Nos. 8400-8999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nos. 9000- (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - CZ series (excluding newspapers) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Korean and Chinese leaflets (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chinese leaflets
    - Nos. 1-4999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Nos. 5000-5999 (excluding newspapers) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Nos. 6000-6999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Nos. 7000-7999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Nos. 8000-8999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newssheet to North Korean civilians (Korean ed.) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Free Korean Newssheet (part of CZ leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Free World News (Korean ed., part of Korean 2600 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Free World Weekly Digest (Chinese ed., part of Chinese 5000 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Free World Weekly Digest (Korean ed., part of Korean 2000 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Home News (English ed., part of Korean 5700 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rehabilitation News (Korean ed., part of Korean 2600 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Tri-Weekly News (Korean ed., part of Korean 2600 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - ROKA Newspaper for NKPA (Korean ed., part of 8300 leaflet series) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - North Korean propaganda leaflets distributed to American military forces (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - North Korean propaganda leaflets for South Korean military forces (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Radio broadcasts of 1st Radio Broadcasting & Leaflet Group, 1952 June (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Radio broadcasts of 1st Radio Broadcasting & Leaflet Group, 1952 July-August (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Korean Pacific Press. News releases from the Washington Bureau., 1950 August 4-1952 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Limb, Ben C. Korea: Test and Symbol.[New York], Republic of Korea Mission to the United Nations, 195-. 11 p. Proposing an election with a view toward the unification of Korea. (Box 3, Folder 38)